Hello everyone, welcome back to English
Pod, my name is Marco and I'm Erica.
And today we're
bringing you another great
advanced lesson for all those
advanced users out there.
That's right, this is a really, really
useful lesson for all of our advanced users.
Exactly, you asked
for a lesson about job
interviews and well, here
we are, we're bringing
you the first of three parts
of the job interview series.
All right, so Marco, you said
it is the first of three parts.
So tell me, what are these three parts?
Okay, in this lesson,
we're going to be
looking at preparing
for a job interview, okay?
So everything you got to do before the job
interview, part two will be talking about
your education, your background,
your work experience, okay?
And in part three,
we'll take a look at some
of the common questions
that are asked at a job interview.
I'm so we'll talk about some great
ways to answer these questions.
Exactly.
These three lessons will be coming
out over the next month or so.
Exactly.
So we're going to
be looking at part one
today, so let's take a look
at some vocabulary preview.
Very cabaret preview.
Well, we have three
words here in vocabulary
preview that you'll hear in
the dialogue in a moment.
And the first one is actually
not really a word, but an acronym.
Right.
CRM.
So Marco, you are our marketing
guy, tell us what is a CRM?
Well, it's really common in marketing.
It stands for customer
relationship management,
okay, or customer
relation management.
But basically, it's the relationship that
the company has with its customers, okay?
So CRM basically has parts like feedback or
customer support, problems that they might
have, and also information
about habits and
likes and dislikes from
their customers or users.
Okay, but I, I commonly
hear this word used as a noun.
So something like, can
you check in the CRM?
Right.
There is some software
out there that's called
the CRM, so sugar CRM, or many different
softwares, which basically manages your
database of customers, basically
software that in globes this whole thing.
Okay.
Got it.
All right.
Our next phrase in
vocabulary preview, custom
designed, custom
designed, custom designed.
So when something is custom designed, it
means it's a special design just for you.
So it's unique.
Right.
That's what the word custom means, unique.
Like made, especially for one person.
Right.
So you have custom
designed or also custom made.
You see that a lot, for
example, in cars, right,
of custom made car, or
maybe a custom built house.
A custom built house with your specific
likes and dislikes, your requirements.
Yep.
Okay.
And our last word, core values,
core values, core values, core values.
So the core values of a company,
what does the core mean, actually?
The center.
The center, right?
Yep.
So in here, I think it's like the
center or the most important.
The most important things
the company believes in, right?
Right.
So maybe respect for the environment,
okay, or developing their employees, okay.
So the core values,
yeah, main things that the
company believes in,
a great phrase for job
interviews.
Oh, yes.
Very good phrase.
Okay.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue.
Erica, what exactly is happening?
All right.
Or we're going to be
listening to two friends.
And this guy is getting
ready to go on a job interview.
So his friend is helping him to prepare.
Okay.
So let's go over everything one more time.
I really want you to get this job.
I know.
It's an amazing growth opportunity.
You're true industry
leaders and it would be
so interesting to be
part of an organization
that is the undisputed leader in
business process platform development.
So let's see.
You did your research
on the company, right?
Well, I visited the website
and read up on what they do.
They're an IT service company
that offers comprehensive
business solutions
for large corporations.
They provide services
such as CRM development
and they also offer
custom design applications.
So what would be your role in the company?
Well, the position is
for an account manager.
That basically means
that I would be the link
between our clients and
our development team.
Sounds good.
And so why do you want to work with them?
Well, as I said, they're
the industry leaders.
They have a really
great growth strategy,
amazing development
opportunities for employees.
And it seems like they have a
strong corporate governance.
They're all about helping companies
grow and unleashing potential.
I guess their core values and
mission really resonated with me.
Oh, and they offer six weeks of
education, stock options and bonuses.
I'm totally going to cash in on that.
You idiot.
You don't say that.
Do you want this job or not?
All right.
So he was doing great, but in the end,
he said something he shouldn't, right?
Yeah, I don't think talking
about money as your
primary motivation for
coming onto a new company.
Yeah, really the way to go.
Yeah, and we're going
to talk about that a little
bit later, but let's take a look real
quick at some language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, in this lesson,
we have five keywords
for you from the dialogue, which
we hope that you will remember.
Mm hmm.
Let's take a look at the first one,
undisputed undisputed undisputed.
So this is kind of a strange word.
Let's listen to some
examples before we explain it.
Example one, it's an undisputed
that she's the best person for the job.
Example two, the undisputed
truth is that unemployment is rising.
No one doubts that example three.
The undisputed champion of the world.
Well, I can understand from these
examples that it means there is no doubt.
There is no doubt.
There's no question.
Okay.
Now let's take a look at our second word,
growth opportunity growth opportunity.
It's a great growth opportunity.
Mm hmm.
So it's an excellent
chance to improve, right?
Improve professionally and
also on a personal side, right?
Yeah, so talking about
growth opportunities,
we can also use the phrase,
a development opportunity.
And it's the same thing.
Yeah.
To develop to grow.
To improve yourself.
Okay.
Now let's take a look at our third
word, read up, read up, read up, read up.
So when you read
up on something, well,
obviously you read it,
right, but you're reading
it specifically for some information so
you can know more about the subject.
So it's kind of similar to study, right?
Kind of.
But really with the
idea that you're trying
to improve your knowledge
about a particular field.
Okay.
Now for our fourth
word, unleash potential,
unleash potential, unleash
potential, unleash potential.
Okay.
So to unleash.
All right.
Well, I'm going to paint a picture for you.
So imagine you have your dog, right?
Mm hmm.
And your dog is walking on a leash, like it
has a string or rope attached to it, right?
So then when you undo
the leash, you unleash
the dog and then what happens,
it goes around and it's running.
Yeah.
It's going everywhere.
Uh huh.
So if you unleash
potential, you release it and
let it go and help it
grow and become bigger.
Yeah.
Exactly.
So you give it freedom.
Uh huh.
So potential is the capabilities or
abilities that a person has, right?
Yeah.
To do something great.
Mm hmm.
Okay.
Unleash potential.
This I think is an excellent
word to use in a job interview.
I think it is really descriptive
and really powerful.
Yeah, it is.
Yeah.
It's a good word.
Uh, okay.
So let's take a look at
our last one now, resonate
with, resonate with,
resonate with, resonate with.
So he mentioned this
really resonated with me.
So what does he mean by resonated?
I guess he means it
connected to him, right?
Mm hmm.
It touched him.
So he agrees with this idea or
he feels that he can relate to it.
Yeah.
Exactly.
This one needs a few examples
to really show its meaning.
Okay.
Let's listen.
Example one.
The candidate speech really
resonated with the voters.
Example two.
Your music doesn't really resonate with me.
Example three.
Your commitment to fight
global warming resonates with me.
All right.
So it's clear now to resonate with, right?
Okay.
So why don't we go
and listen to our dialogue
for the last time and
then we'll come back
and give you some great pointers
about preparing for a job interview.
Okay.
So let's go over everything one more time.
I really want you to get this job.
I know.
It's an amazing growth opportunity.
They're true industry leaders.
And it would be so
interesting to be part of
an organization that is
the undisputed leader
in business process
platform development.
So let's see.
You did your research
on the company, right?
Wow.
I visited the website and
read up on what they do.
They're an IT service company
that offers comprehensive
business solutions
for large corporations.
They provide services
such as CRM development
and they also offer
custom design applications.
So what would be your role in the company?
Well, the position is
for an account manager.
That basically means
that I would be the link
between our clients and
our development team.
Sounds good.
And so why do you want to work with them?
Well, as I said, they're
the industry leaders.
They have a really
great growth strategy,
amazing development
opportunities for employees.
And it seems like they have a
strong corporate governance.
They're all about helping companies
grow and unleashing potential.
I guess their core values and
mission really resonated with me.
Oh, and they offer six weeks of
education, stock options and bonuses.
I'm totally going to cash in on that.
You idiot.
You don't say that.
Do you want this job or not?
Okay.
So preparing for a job interview
is really important, right?
Yes.
Yeah.
And we're going to
give you some really basic
tips about how you can
prepare for a job interview.
Yeah.
I got to confess something to you, Marco.
What?
Yeah.
I love job interviews.
Really?
Yeah.
I know it's really weird.
Most people hate them, but I love them.
So you love being the interviewer
or going to job interviews.
Both.
Really.
Yeah.
I like everything about them.
So I feel like I have a lot of
passion to share with you about this.
All right.
So let's take a look
at the first point or
the first tip that you
can help us out with.
So before you go to a job interview, you
should do a little bit of research, right?
Right.
And that's our first point.
It's really important
to know as much as you
can about the company,
their history, their
product, their management
style, just as much
information as you can find out
about how they work and what they do.
Uh-huh.
And why do you think this is important?
Well, basically, you'll be asked
about it in the interview, right?
And so if you show that
you haven't prepared,
you haven't done any research,
you show that you don't care.
One of the best ways that
you can impress in a job
interview is to show that
you know about the company.
And important things
like you know what kind
of products they offer or
what's their largest market.
And I guess that really
impresses the interviewer
because it shows
that you are interested
in this company and
they really want the job.
And that you are willing to do the
extra work it takes to prepare yourself.
So I think that will
show the interviewer that
later on when you're working for
them, you'll do that extra work on the job.
Exactly.
That's a really good point.
So that's our first point, our
first tip, to do some research.
Yes.
You've done your research, you
know everything about the company.
What else should you do?
Once you've read up on
the company, you've got
to spend some time
thinking about yourself.
You've got to prepare to
sell yourself to the company.
So to sell yourself to
really demonstrate them
why you are the perfect
person for the job.
Right.
Because a lot of people think about why
they want to work for the company, right?
Because they feel like
they're aligned with
the core values or the message of
the company resonates with them.
But what the interviewer
really wants to hear
is how you, the interviewee, is
going to benefit the company.
What are you going to bring to the company?
Right.
And this is the most important part
is to know what are your skills, right?
Yes.
And it's not enough to just say,
well, I am a great leader, right?
So if you are a great leader,
you should be ready to give an
example of how you have
demonstrated to be a great leader, right?
Yes.
All right.
So maybe like an example, like I'm a really
strong leader because in my previous job,
I had the best JD power
ratings for employee satisfaction.
Okay.
So you are actually showing with numbers
or with facts that you are a great leader.
Yeah.
So the key thing here, I think, is identify
what your strengths and skills are.
Think of specific examples.
If you can give numbers
and show how you can
bring this skill and your
experiences to the new company.
And now, well, you're
ready to sell yourself.
You've done your research.
Now you have all of
these things in your mind.
You have to practice.
Yes.
Right?
A much overlooked stage in the preparation.
Yeah.
A lot of people think it through, they write
things down, but don't really practice.
Yeah.
So I know you have a few tips about how
you can practice interviewing effectively.
Mm hmm.
Okay.
Well, the first thing that you
should do is use your friends.
Yeah.
They got to be good for something.
Exactly.
And well, probably
your friends are also
working at a company,
maybe their managers, or
maybe they've interviewed
someone before already.
So you can set up a
mini interview and have
them pretend that they
are the interviewer and
ask you these questions and
you're trying to answer seriously.
And I'm sure that your
friends can give you
some great feedback, maybe what
you did right, maybe what you did wrong.
So that's a really good way.
And another thing is also
you can record yourself.
Yes.
Right?
Yeah.
If you have a video camera
or even a web, I mean,
many people have a webcam
like right in your laptop.
Record yourself actually doing the
practice interview with your friends.
And this is really
useful because you can
later see what you
recorded and detect some of
the things that maybe
aren't really useful or good.
You know, for example, posture
is a really important aspect.
So what do you mean posture?
So the way that you
are sitting down in your
seat and how you
are expressing yourself
with your hands, yeah,
some people, you know,
they move a lot during the,
because of course you're nervous.
Maybe they're moving
from side to side or
playing with their feet
or playing with something
on the table or moving their
hands in an awkward way.
So those are the things that
you have to watch out for.
Yes.
So I guess it's really important to sit up
straight and to show that you are powerful
and in control.
And another really great
thing is eye contact, right?
Yeah.
We were talking about this earlier.
And why is eye contact so important?
If an interviewee
maintains eye contact with
me for like most of the interview, I feel
like they have really good people skills.
In my opinion, I would say
they have a lot of self confidence.
Yeah.
I'd agree.
Because if a person is looking
down or not looking directly
at you, it's either one of
two things in my opinion.
It's either they are not confident enough
with themselves or they are lying to you.
Yes.
Right.
Yeah.
Or also they just they don't
have good people skills.
Yeah.
Which is a problem in today's
sort of knowledge based economy.
Exactly.
So it's really important
to maintain eye contact
and one other really important thing related
to eye contact posture is the handshake.
Mm-hmm.
When you get to the
interview, it's really,
really important to give
a firm good handshake.
So what qualifies as a firm good handshake?
Well, you don't have to prove
that you are ultra strong, right?
So you don't have to
squeeze the other person's
hand really hard and
like break their hands.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's not like a strength contest.
No.
A good firm handshake
is squeezing normally
not too tight, not too
loose, but your entire
palm, your entire hand has to be in contact
with the other person's palm or hand.
Yes.
Don't give them the fingers.
Yeah.
Like some people give you only
four fingers or half their hand.
Yeah.
I hate that.
I hate it too.
And this goes for men and for
women because a lot of women do this.
Yeah.
I call this the dead fish handshake.
The dead fish.
It is kind of like a dead fish
or the dead hand handshake.
Yeah.
I absolutely agree with you on this one.
So nice firm handshake.
Yep.
Firm handshake.
And, well, these are
our tips for preparing
for the interview and everything
you have to do before it.
I'm sure there are a lot
more things out there.
So and I'm sure our users
have some insight on this as well.
Yeah.
I'd love to hear it because like
I told you, I love job interviews.
Yeah.
So come to our website at EnglishPod.com.
Leave us your comments.
Maybe you've had a
good experience with a job
interview or maybe a
bad one or maybe even
as an interviewer, you've interviewed
some really interesting people.
And you've got some
great tips to share with us.
Exactly.
So come to our website.
Leave your questions.
Leave your comments.
Share your experiences
with our other users.
And Eric and I will also be there
to participate in the discussion.
All right, guys.
Well, thanks for listening.
And until next time, goodbye.